We're going to do an exercise where we cover our syntax errors, our custom exceptions, talk
about tri-accept, and see how we might be able to re-raise errors.
Some common types of exceptions we've seen, I try to define a function, and I don't put
it in the right indentation, I'll get an indentation error here.
We saw syntax error yesterday, it's a little bit harder to trigger syntax error for a list
here, but let's say it did something like that, that's a syntax error, invalid syntax, and
put in the value.
If I try to do this, and I forgot the comma between the last two values, it's also
a syntax error, so some common exceptions that we might see, one divided by zero, that's
that zero division error that we've seen, and some of those other common exceptions are
type error, so if we try to add an integer in a string, that's an unsupported
operand right, we would need to call, stir, on that number, before we can concatenate them
together, a value error like we saw earlier, if I try to make an integer out of a string
a, it's a value error, I'd say, I don't know what this is, is a number, and lastly,
the key error, so if I try to make a dictionary, with that, hello, for the key and a world
has the value for that key, and I try to use a key that doesn't exist, and I get a key error.
In terms of raising our own exceptions, the classes that we make should inherit from exception,
and generally end with, usually you'll see error, very occasionally you'll see exception,
but usually naming these errors more common, as you've seen the type error value error,
key error, et cetera, so to follow that convention, let me name this my error, and subclass
from exception, do I need to have anything in this class, or can it just be empty, right?
And to, to raise this exception, I use the raised key word, and that'll generate that
trace back there.
I can also make my own custom exceptions a little bit fancier, so I can say class my error,
extends from exception, and provide my own constructor, and say self and message.
And now I'm going to change my message, and it's going to say error, system, failure.
I mean, that's a really serious error, followed by the message, and what do I need to
do, so that this, my new message is propagated up, super, super, right, and super will
call the constructor on which class, exception, right, so we're going to need to call dot in
it there, and we're going to pass in our new message.
Now, if I raise my error, is this going to work, it won't, because message is required,
and I did not provide one, so I'm going to provide a helpful error message here, well,
okay, and that's what we get.
Programming is very serious, it's very serious business, no laughing a lot in this class,
just kidding.
Okay, I'm trying accept if I have a dictionary here, the key is hello, and the value for
that key is world.
I can try to print out my dictionary, that look for random key, it's not in there, right?
So what do I want to catch in this instance, which type of key are, yep, oops, I think I messed
up my, let's see, right here, forgot that closing parentheses, okay, I'm going to accept
on here and print no key found, okay, works as expected, I can also add a label to that exception
if I wanted to do anything with it, generally more useful for our own custom exceptions,
right?
Let's say I was going to try, you know, getting some random key here, and I could accept
on key error, and how do I give a variable name to that error, right, has, let's say as
E, and now I can print out an upstream, and it'll say, oh no, the key, and now I can be,
the key doesn't exist, and I can say error was here, we can also re-raise exceptions,
so catching a, you know, runtime error or something, and then raising one of our own custom
exceptions, that might be a good case for one, so I had the class my exception, and just
as a reminder here, when I raise my exception, I got that, I'm sorry, I called it my error,
when I raise my error, I get this very helpful message, right, so maybe what I want to
do here is I'm going to loop over a range of numbers, and I'm going to do that in reverse,
so if I call range with 0 and 5 and negative 1, I'm going to show you this as a list,
sorry, that's not what I want, I'm going to start at 0, start at 5, go to 0, so if I wanted
to print out a list of, go through a range of numbers in reverse, I would do the end value
first, the start value second, so kind of flip that around and then pass in a negative
number here, and as a reminder, that second argument is not inclusive, and so if I want
to go to 0, we have to put minus 1 there, right, so I'm going to loop over this and say
for num in this range, print out 5 divided by the number, and eventually it's going to get
to 0 and say 0 division error, so instead, I can put this whole thing in a try, right, and
print out 5 divided by the number, okay, just to show you, we had my, you know, my error that
I can raise, and I'm going to loop over this list of numbers, and I'm going to put this
in a try block, and I'm going to say try to divide 5 by that number, I'm going to accept
on the 0 division error, and then I'm going to raise a different type of error, I'm going
to raise my error, and say, you know, well, you tried to divide by 0, okay, so we'll see that
in the repule, I'll say during the handling of that exception, another exception occurred,
you won't see that particular detail in your trace backs when you run Python programs,
so this exception caused another one, and I re-raised, I caught this one, and I raised another
one, and so, you know, what are you trying to do here?